They're not that nice.
The Nice Guys is a comedy, crime, action film directed by Shane Black.
A private eye investigates the apparent suicide of a fading porn
star in 1970s Los Angeles and uncovers a conspiracy.
Jackson Healy, played by Russell Crowe.
Holland March, played by Ryan Gosling.
Holly March, played by Angourie Rice.
John Boy, played by Matt Bomer.
Amelia Kuttner, played by Margaret Qualley.
Tally, played by Yaya DaCosta.
The Nice Guys is a 2016 American neo-noir action comedy film directed by
Shane Black, who co-wrote the screenplay with Anthony Bagarozzi.
The film stars Russell Crowe and Ryan Gosling in the title roles, with Angourie Rice, Matt Bomer,
Margaret Qualley, Keith David, and Kim Basinger appearing in supporting roles.
Set in the 70s Los Angeles, the film focuses on private eye Holland March (Gosling) and tough enforcer for hire
Jackson Healy (Crowe) who team up to investigate the disappearance of a teenage girl (Qualley).
The Nice Guys premiered on May 10, 2016, in Hollywood, screened on May 15 at
the 2016 Cannes Film Festival and was released by Warner Bros.
Pictures in the United States on May 20, 2016, receiving positive reviews from critics for its humor, mystery, and the
performances of Crowe and Gosling but it flopped at the box office as it grossed $63 million on a $50 million budget.
The film has gained a cult following especially for
Gosling and Crowe's chemistry and comedy.
The film explores themes of daughter, pornography,
detective, 1970s, investigation.
The tone is lighthearted and dark.